<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[]]></SubHeading>
     	<PageText><pText><![CDATA[In device identification and categorization for discovery, there are different solutions for generating unique address like Electronic Product Codes (EPC), Universal Product Code (UPC), Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) and IP addresses like IPv6. There are different device classification solutions like United Nations Standard Products and Services Code (UNSPSC)* and eCl@ss **. (UNSPSC)* is an open, global, multi-sector standard for efficient, accurate, flexible classification of products and services. eCl@ss ** is the standard for classification and clear description of cross-industry products.]]></pText></PageText>
       <PageText><pText><![CDATA[In syntactic interoperability for device interaction, the interoperability between devices and device user is in terms of message formats. The message format from a device to a user should be understandable for the user’s computer. On the other hand, the message format from the user to the device should be executable by the device. Some popular approaches in this regard are Service-Oriented Computing (SOC) based architecture, Web services, RESTful Web services, Open standard protocols such as IEEE 802.15.4, IEEE 802.15.1, Wireless Hart and closed protocols such as Z-wave. But Wireless Hart and Z-wave are incompatible with each other. There are middleware technologies like software middleware bridge which dynamically map physical devices with different domains. Based on the map, the devices can be discovered and controlled remotely. In cross-content syntactic interoperability, the exchange of messages takes place using XML syntax.]]></pText></PageText>
       <PageText><pText><![CDATA[In semantic interoperability for device interaction, the interoperability between devices and device user is in terms of the meaning of messages. The device can understand the meaning of user’s instruction that is sent from the user to the device. Similarly, the user can understand the meaning of device’s response sent from the device. One of the approaches for semantic interoperability is ontology based approach which includes device ontology, physical domain ontology and estimation ontology. But ontology based solution is limited to the defined domain or context. Another approach is the collaborative conceptualization theory. In this the object is defined based on the collaborative concept, which is called cosign. The representation of a collaborative sign (cosign) is defined as follows.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText><pText><![CDATA[Cosign of an object = (A, B, C, D), where A is a cosign internal identifier, B is a natural language, C is the context of A and D is a definition of the object. An example for CCTV cosign is given as cosign=(1234, English, CCTV, “Camera Type: Bullet, Communication: Network/IP, Horizontal Resolution: 2048 TVL”). This solution approach is applicable for different domains or contexts.]]></pText></PageText>
      
      <PageText><pText><![CDATA[<b>Device Interoperability</b><br>
      A solution approach for device interoperability is Universal Middleware Bridge (UMB). UMB solves seamless interoperability problems caused by the heterogeneity of several kinds of home network middleware. UMB creates virtual maps among the physical devices of all middleware home networks such as HAVI, Jini, LonWorks and UPnP. It creates compatibility among these middleware home networks. Figure 5.18 shows the architecture of Universal Middleware Bridge (UMB). UMB consists of UMB core (UMB-C) and UMB adaptor (UMB-A).]]></pText></PageText>
  </PageData>
</main>