<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[]]></SubHeading>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[mission may require a flight plan update. For example, while a multi-UAV system is operated for a search and rescue mission; after the arrival of a new intelligence report, the mission may be concentrated on a certain area and the flight plan update also affects FANET parameters. FANET design should be developed so that it can adjust itself against any changes or failures. FANET physical layer should adapt according to the node density, distance between nodes and environmental changes. It can scan the parameters and choose the most appropriate physical layer option. The highly dynamic nature of FANET environment also affects network layer protocols. Route maintenance in an ad hoc network is closely related to the topology changes. Thus, the performance of the system depends on the routing protocol in adapting to link changes. Transport layer should also be adapted according to the status of FANET.
      	]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Scalability:</b><br> Collaborative work of UAVs can improve the performance of the system in comparison to a single-UAV system. In fact, this is the main motivation to use multi-UAV based systems. In many applications, the performance enhancement is closely related with the number of UAVs. For example, the higher number of UAVs can complete a search and rescue operation faster. FANET protocols and algorithms should be designed so that any number of UAVs can operate together with minimal performance degradation.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Latency:</b><br>Latency is one of the most important design issues for all types of networks and FANET is not an exception. FANET latency requirement is fully dependent on the application. Especially for real-time FANET applications, such as military monitoring, the data packets must be delivered within a certain delay bound. Another low latency requirement is valid for collision avoidance of multiple UAVs. The packet delay behaviors are different for MANETs and FANETs and the protocols developed for MANET may not satisfy the latency requirements of FANET. New FANET protocols and algorithms are needed for delay sensitive multi-UAV applications.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>UAV Platform Constraints:</b><br>FANET communication hardware must be deployed on the UAV platform and this situation imposes certain constraints. The weight of the hardware is an important issue for the performance of the UAVs. Lighter hardware means lighter payload, and it extends the endurance. Another opportunity that comes with the lighter communication hardware is to deploy additional sensors on the UAV. If the total payload is assumed as constant and the communication hardware is lighter, more advanced sensors and other peripherals can be deployed. Space limitation is another UAV platform related constraints for FANET designs. Especially for mini UAVs, the space limitation is very important for communication hardware that must be fitted into the UAV platform.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Bandwidth  requirement:</b><br> In most of the FANET applications, the aim is to collect  data from the environment and to relay the collected data to a ground base. For example, in surveillance, monitoring or rescue operations; the image or video of the target area must be relayed from the UAV to the command control center with a very strict delay bound and it requires high bandwidth. In addition, by the help of the technological advancements on sensor technologies, it is possible to collect data with very high resolution and this makes the bandwidth requirement much higher. The collaboration and coordination of multiple UAVs]]></pText></PageText>
  </PageData>
</main>
 
