<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[]]></SubHeading>
       <PageText><pText><![CDATA[ <ol class="DecimalNumberClass">
       	<li><b>Manufacturing</b><br>Every manufacturing environment whether it is food processing or general product manufacturing relies on technology, to ensure costs are managed properly and processes are executed efficiently. Automating manufacturing processes within such a fast-paced environment is expected to improve processes even more. In the manufacturing world, this could involve highly automated equipment maintenance and safety procedures. For example, M2M tools allow business owners to be alerted on their smart phones when an important piece of equipment needs servicing, so they can address issues as quickly as they arise. Sophisticated networks of sensors connected to the Internet could even order replacement parts automatically.</li>

       <li><b>Home Appliances</b><br>IoT already affects home appliance connectivity through platforms like Nest. However, M2M is expected to take home-based IoT to the next level. Manufacturers like LG and Samsung are already slowly unveiling smart home appliances to help ensure a higher quality of life for occupants. For example, an M2M-capable washing machine could send alerts to the owners’ smart devices once it finishes washing or drying and a smart refrigerator could automatically order groceries from Amazon once its inventory is depleted. There are many more examples of home automation that can potentially improve quality of life for residents, including systems that allow members of the household to remotely control Heating Ventilation and Air Conditioning (HVAC) systems using their mobile devices. In situations where a homeowner decides to leave work early, he or she could contact the home heating system before leaving work to make sure the temperature at home will be comfortable upon arrival. He/she can contact the lighting system also so that the necessary lights will be on before he/she reaches home.</li>

     <li><b>Healthcare Device Management</b><br>One of the biggest opportunities for M2M technology is in the realm of health care. With M2M technology, hospitals can automate processes to ensure the highest levels of treatment. Using devices that can react faster than a human healthcare professional in an emergency situation make this possible. For instance, when a patient’s vital signs drop below normal, an M2M-connected life support device could automatically administer oxygen and additional care until a healthcare professional arrives on the scene. M2M also allows patients to be monitored in their own homes instead of in hospitals or care centers. For example, devices that track a frail or elderly person’s normal movements can detect when he or she has had a fall and alert a healthcare worker to the situation.
     Telemedicine offers another use. For instance, some heart patients wear special monitors that gather information about the way their heart is working. The data is sent to implanted devices that deliver a shock to correct an errant rhythm.</li></ol>
     ]]></pText> </PageText>
     </PageData>
 </main>