<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[]]></SubHeading>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[nodes are remarkably close to the ground and in many case, there is no line-of-sight between the sender and the receiver. Therefore, radio signals are mostly affected by the geographical structure of the terrain. However, FANET nodes can be far away from the ground and in most of the cases, there is a line-of-sight between UAVs.]]></pText></PageText>

   <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Power Consumption and Network  Lifetime:</b><br>Network lifetime is a key design issue  for MANETs, which especially consist of battery-powered computing devices. Developing energy efficient communication protocols is the goal of efforts to increase the network lifetime. Especially, while the battery-powered computing devices are getting smaller in MANETs, system developers have to pay more attention to the energy efficient communication protocols to prolong the lifetime of the network. However, FANET communication hardware is powered by the energy source of the UAV. This means FANET communication hardware has no practical power resource problem as in MANET. In this case, FANET designs may not be power sensitive, unlike most of the MANET applications. However, it must be stated that power consumption still can be a design problem for mini UAVs.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Computational Power:</b><br>In ad hoc network concept, the nodes can act as routers. Therefore, they must have certain computation capabilities to process incoming data in real- time. Generally, MANET nodes are battery powered small computers such as laptops, PDAs and smart phones. Because of the size and energy constraints, the nodes have only limited computational power. On the other hand, both in VANETs and FANETs, application specific devices with high computational power can be used. Most of the UAVs have enough energy and space to include high computational power. The only limitation about the computational power is the weight. By the help of the hardware miniaturization tendency, it is possible to put powerful computation hardware in UAV platforms. However, the size and weight limitation can still constitute serious constraints for mini UAVs that have very limited payload capacity.]]></pText></PageText>
      <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Localization:</b><br>Accurate geospatial localization is at the core of mobile and cooperative ad hoc networks. Existing localization methods include global positioning system (GPS), beacon (or anchor) nodes, and proximity-based localization. In MANET, GPS is generally used to receive the coordinates of a mobile communication terminal and most of the time, GPS is sufficient to determine the location of the nodes. When GPS is not available, such as in dense foliage areas, beacon nodes or proximity-based techniques can also be used. In VANET, for a navigation-grade GPS receiver, there is about 10–15 m accuracy, which can be acceptable for route guidance. However, it is not sufficient for cooperative safety applications, such as collision warnings for cars. Some researchers use assisted GPS (AGPS) or differential GPS (DGPS) by using some type of ground-based reference stations for range corrections with accuracy about 10 cm .]]></pText></PageText>
       <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[Because of the high speed and different mobility models of multi-UAV systems, FANET needs highly accurate localization data with smaller time intervals. GPS provides position information at one-second interval and it may not be sufficient for certain FANET protocols. In this case, each UAV must be equipped with a GPS and an inertial measurement unit (IMU) to offer the position to the other UAVs at any time. IMU can be calibrated by the GPS signal]]></pText></PageText>
  </PageData>
</main> 